<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<!--
    Copyright 2015 Actian Corporation

    Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
    you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
    You may obtain a copy of the License at

        http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

    Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
    distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
    WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
    See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
    limitations under the License.
-->
<knimeNode icon="./JSON.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>JSONPath Runner</name>
    <shortDescription>Node for generating text using using the JSONPath template engine</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node uses the Jayway JsonPath library to extract text from JSON objects.

            <p>
                <a href="https://github.com/jayway/JsonPath">https://github.com/jayway/JsonPath</a>
            </p>
            <br />This site has good examples of JSONPath expressions as well as an online expression evaluator.
            <br />
            <br />Another good resource on JSONPath is the following site:
            <p>
                <a href="http://goessner.net/articles/JsonPath/">JSONPath - XPath for JSON</a>
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="JSONPath Mappings">A list of JSONPath mapping specifications.<br />
            <br />The first column specifies the source field name for a JSON object.  Once a source field is defined
            subsequent mappings that use the same source field do not need to respecify the source field.
            <br />
            <br />The second column specifies output field for the JSONPath expression results.   An output field must
            be specified for each mapping.
            <br />
            <br />The third column is used to indicate if the JSONPath expression results get flat mapped to multiple
            output records.  If the expression result produces a list then each element of the list will appear in
            subsequent output records.   In cases where there are multiple flat mapped output lists the longest list
            determines how many records are generated.
            <br />
            <br />The last column contains the JSONPath expression used to query data from the source JSON object.   An
            expression is required for each mapping.
        </option>
        <option name="Add">Create a new entry in the table.  A default name and expression will be generated.</option>
        <option name="Remove">Remove the currently selected field derivation.</option>
        <option name="Remove All">Deletes all defined field derivation.</option>
        <option name="Move Up">Move the currently selected field derivation up.</option>
        <option name="Move Down">Move the currently selected field derivation down.</option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Source records">Source records</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Output records">Output records.   The schema used for the output port is a combination of
            the input schema and the list of output (text) fields from the JSONPath mappings.
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Rejected records">Records with JSON parse errors.  The schema for the reject record
            port is a combination of the source record schema and an error text field.
        </outPort>
    </ports>

</knimeNode>
